Israel Ministry of Finance, 1 Kaplan Street, Jerusalem, 9195015 (972) 054-779-2201 ****almarottem@gmail.com **≥** almar@mof.gov.il **≥**

ALMA ROTTEM

research interests Political economy, applied game theory, labor economics, economic history.

I am interested in the imagining and designing of new political mechanisms and institutions in response to major economic and technological changes. I am also interested in the dynamics of democratic institutions and labor unions.

education

M.A., History, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, present

MPhil, Economics, University of Oxford, 2021

Graduated with Merit

 $Dissertation: \ The \ Trade of Fopulism: \ A \ Spatial \ Elections \ Model \ with \ Rent-extraction \ and$

Uncertain Extremism

B.A., Liberal Arts and Sciences (Joint Degree) with Distinction,

Amsterdam University College, 2019

Majored in economics

GPA: 4.0. Graduated summa cum laude

research experience

Research Economist and Head of Research, Department of Salary and Labor Agreements, Israel Ministry of Finance, 2021-present

Heading research on public sector wages and employment (team of 3)

Write and publish reports, policy briefs, and analyses

Assist in preparation for wage negotiations with labor unions and legislative processes Forthcoming project: Analyzing the unadjusted gender pay gap using salary data

Research Assistant, Tel Aviv University, 2021

Research on social media consumption and polarization, under Dr. Ro'ee Levy

Intern, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), 2021

Economic and Policy Analysis of Climate Change (EPIC)

Research Assistant, Nuffield College, University of Oxford, 2020-2021 Research on British elections, under Prof. Jane Green

Research Assistant, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam (VU Amsterdam), 2018
Assisted Prof. Remco Oostendorp in pre-field survey work in development economics

other experience

skills

Data Analyst and Head Data Analyst, Owlin B.V., 2017-2019

Reporter, Broadcaster and Editor, Galei Tzahal (IDF national radio), 2012-2015

Editor-in-chief of a one of Israel's high-rated daily interviews program

Languages: English (native), Hebrew (native)

Programming languages and softwares: R, Stata, SQL, LaTeX, CSPro